LAURA E. COLLINS FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT DETAILS

615-720-4240

@ laura.e.collins1@gmail.com

<u>lauracollins.dev</u>

in linkedin.com/in/laura-e-collins/

github.com/LaCollins

PROFILE

I have multi-industry experience and strong communication, planning and problem solving abilities. I have worked in a variety of professional fields, which has allotted me a rather diverse and well rounded skill set.

As an artist, I am naturally creative and posses the inclination to think "outside the box". One of my biggest strengths, is my ability to self-educate. I have a passion and love for learning and continuously seek to further my knowledge.

In my youth, I learned to program in Basic, Visual Basic, C++, and HTML 3.2. However, I decided to take a path that led me away from tech. After many years, I have circled back to bring technology and programming into the forefront of my life and pursue a career in development.

PROJECTS

Front End Capstone - Snakelings

Snakes are a valuable asset to our ecosystem, but due to misinformation and misunderstanding, thousands of snakes lose their lives to terrified humans. I wanted to create an application that would allow users to identify snake species quickly, learn more about the species, and determine whether or not the species was venomous or not. I also wanted users to be able to track and report snake sightings.

I had a lot of fun building this project with React, and used Bootstrap and React Bootstrap, combined with SCSS to flesh out the user interface. Additionally, I used React-AWS-S3 to allow users to upload images into an AWS S3 Bucket directly from their computer or phone.

- Github: https://github.com/LaCollins/snakelings
- Live Site: https://snakelings.com

Group Project - Jurassic World

This group project was designed as a faux business page for Jurassic World. This app allows the user to keep track of the dinosaurs, staff, rides, vendors, equipment, and schedules.

This project was built using JQuery and ES6. The UI was designed using CSS and Bootstrap. Additionally, I used CRON to schedule a random "Chaos Monkey" event to happen at the same time every day.

- Github: https://github.com/nss-evening-cohort-10/nutshell-jurassic-world
- Live Site: https://jurassic-world-a9907.web.app/

EDUCATION HISTORY

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL
Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp
UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA - CLA

B.A., Japanese Langauge and Literature

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Web Developer | 2019 - Present

Twelve month full-stack web development bootcamp that focuses on introducing development through hands-on intensive projects

- Utilize GitHub for source code version control
- Built browser based applications in vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, React, HTML5, SCSS, JSX, AWS, and Bootstrap
- Works collaboratively on group projects using GitHub and Firebase
- Participate in daily scrum and regular code review

PANERA BREAD

Baker Training Specialist | 2017 - Present

An international chain restaurant focused on soup, sandwiches, and baked goods

- Supervise staff of 20 employees across 10 cafes throughout Nashville
- Oversee Baker training via hands on, side-by-side instruction and coaching
- Manage relations between bakery staff and cafe management
- Use creative problem solving to manage staffing and troubleshoot quality control issues
- Brought turnover down from 105% to 43%, the lowest turnover in the region, within a year
- Promoted twice in less than a year

Certified Baker/ Certified Baker Trainer | 2016-2017

GALLATIN POLICE DEPARTMENT

Public Safety Dispatcher | 2015 - 2016

- Prioritized responses to public emergency and non-emergent calls to efficiently dispatch police, fire and EMS while tracking data in real-time while maintaining a calm composure
- Took caller information, read associated computer information and documented vital details in call tracking and assignment system
- Used radio, telephone and computer system to update first responders with new information

TARGET

P.Fresh Assistant | 2015

- Cross-trained in all sales associate roles including logistic team roles such as shipping and receiving in order to provide skilled back-up for all teams
- Interacted with customers and retail buyers to follow-up on shipping statuses and expedited orders
- Analyzed the store's inventory, back-stocked overstock, and ordered merchandise and products when stock levels were low
- Addressed discrepancies to maintain record keeping validity

Back Room Associate | 2013 - 2015

- Maintained an organized stock room and performed regular inventory audits to ensure correct inventory
- Packaged and prepared products for shipping to fulfill online orders

Flow Team | 2012 - 2013

• Unloaded incoming merchandise and stocked sales floor shelves

HANDISHOP INDUSTRIES, LLC.

Vocational Rehabilitator | 2010 - 2012

A workshop for developing vocational skills for adults with disabilities

 Created and taught tailored curriculum to clients to develop social and vocational skills which resulted in marked improvement in client productivity, social behavior, and responsibility

A TOUCH OF HOME, LLC.

Nursing Assistant | 2009 - 2010

An assisted living facility for elderly residents

- Assisted elderly residents with personal cares
- Kept records of resident vital signs and assisted PRN as needed